{
  "title": "Art of War Quotes",
  "description": "A list of famous quotes from Sun Tzu",
  "tags": [{ "value": "Getting Started" }],
  "cards": [
    {
      "front":
        "The general who wins the battle makes ____ calculations in his temple before the battle is fought. The general who loses makes but ___ calculations beforehand.",
      "back":
        "The general who wins the battle makes many calculations in his temple before the battle is fought. The general who loses makes but few calculations beforehand."
    },
    {
      "front": "A leader leads by _____ not by ____.",
      "back": "A leader leads by example not by force."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "The control of a large force is the ____ _______ as the control of a few men: it is merely a question of _______ ___ their numbers.",
      "back":
        "The control of a large force is the same principle as the control of a few men: it is merely a question of dividing up their numbers."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "The ultimate in disposing one's troops is to be without ascertainable ______. Then the most penetrating spies cannot pry in nor can the wise lay plans against you.",
      "back":
        "The ultimate in disposing one's troops is to be without ascertainable shape. Then the most penetrating spies cannot pry in nor can the wise lay plans against you."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "If words of command are not clear and distinct, if orders are not thoroughly understood, the _______ is to blame. But if his orders ARE clear, and the soldiers nevertheless disobey, then it is the fault of _____.",
      "back":
        "If words of command are not clear and distinct, if orders are not thoroughly understood, the general is to blame. But if his orders ARE clear, and the soldiers nevertheless disobey, then it is the fault of their officers."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "Strategy without ______ is the slowest route to victory. ______ without strategy is the noise before defeat.",
      "back":
        "Strategy without tactics is the slowest route to victory. Tactics without strategy is the noise before defeat."
    },
    {
      "front": "All warfare is based on ______.",
      "back": "All warfare is based on deception."
    },
    {
      "front": "If ______ is sure to result in victory, then you must _____.",
      "back": "If fighting is sure to result in victory, then you must fight."
    },
    {
      "front": "One defends when his strength is ______, he attacks when it is _______.",
      "back": "One defends when his strength is inadaquate, he attacks when it is abundant."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "The quality of _______ is like the well-timed swoop of a falcon which enables it to strike and destroy its victim.",
      "back":
        "The quality of decision is like the well-timed swoop of a falcon which enables it to strike and destroy its victim."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "When the enemy is at ease, be able to ____ him; when well fed, to _____ him; when at rest, to make him ____. Appear at places to which he must hasten; move swiftly where he does not expect you.",
      "back":
        "When the enemy is at ease, be able to weary him; when well fed, to starve him; when at rest, to make him move. Appear at places to which he must hasten; move swiftly where he does not expect you."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "If you know your ____ and you know _____ you need not fear the results of a hundred battles. If you know ______ but not the _____ for every victory gained you will also suffer a defeat. If you know neither, you will succumb in every battle.",
      "back":
        "If you know your enemy and you know yourself you need not fear the results of a hundred battles. If you know yourself but not the enemy for every victory gained you will also suffer a defeat. If you know neither the enemy nor yourself you will succumb in every battle."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "The general who advances without coveting _____ and retreats without fearing _____, whose only thought is to protect his country and do good service for his sovereign, is the jewel of the kingdom.",
      "back":
        "The general who advances without coveting fame and retreats without fearing disgrace, whose only thought is to protect his country and do good service for his sovereign, is the jewel of the kingdom."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "For to win one hundred victories in one hundred battles is not the acme of skill. To _____ the enemy without fighting is the acme of skill.",
      "back":
        "For to win one hundred victories in one hundred battles is not the acme of skill. To subdue the enemy without fighting is the acme of skill."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "What the ancients called a clever fighter is one who not only wins, but excels in winning with _____.",
      "back":
        "What the ancients called a clever fighter is one who not only wins, but excels in winning with ease."
    },
    {
      "front": "To a surrounded enemy, you must leave a way of _____.",
      "back": "To a surrounded enemy, you must leave a way of escape."
    },
    {
      "front": "To know your _____, you must become your _____.",
      "back": "To know your Enemy, you must become your Enemy."
    },
    {
      "front": "Thus, what is of supreme importance in war is to attack the enemy's _______.",
      "back": "Thus, what is of supreme importance in war is to attack the enemy's strategy."
    },
    {
      "front": "A leader leads by _____, not _____.",
      "back": "A leader leads by example, not force."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "Too frequent _____ indicate that the general is at the end of his resources; too frequent _______ that he is in acute distress.",
      "back":
        "Too frequent rewards indicate that the general is at the end of his resources; too frequent punishments that he is in acute distress."
    },
    {
      "front": "Pretend _____ and encourage his ______.",
      "back": "Pretend inferiority and encourage his arrogance."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "All men can see these ______ whereby I conquer, but what none can see is the ______ out of which victory is evolved.",
      "back":
        "All men can see these tactics whereby I conquer, but what none can see is the strategy out of which victory is evolved."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "If we do not wish to fight, we can prevent the enemy from engaging us even though the lines of our encampment be merely traced out on the ground. All we need to do is to throw something ___ and ______ in his way.",
      "back":
        "If we do not wish to fight, we can prevent the enemy from engaging us even though the lines of our encampment be merely traced out on the ground. All we need to do is to throw something odd and unaccountable in his way."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "A military operation involves _______. Even though you are competent, appear to be ________. Though effective, appear to be ________.",
      "back":
        "A military operation involves deception. Even though you are competent, appear to be incompetent. Though effective, appear to be ineffective."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "_____ warriors win first and then go to war, while _______ warriors go to war first and then seek to win.",
      "back":
        "Victorious warriors win first and then go to war, while defeated warriors go to war first and then seek to win."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "The best victory is when the opponent _______ of its own accord before there are any actual hostilities... It is best to win without fighting.",
      "back":
        "The best victory is when the opponent surrenders of its own accord before there are any actual hostilities... It is best to win without fighting."
    },
    {
      "front": "_______ multiply as they are seized.",
      "back": "Opportunities multiply as they are seized."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "______ is the essence of war. Take advantage of the enemy's _________; travel by unexpected routes and strike him where he has taken no precautions.",
      "back":
        "Speed is the essence of war. Take advantage of the enemy's unpreparedness; travel by unexpected routes and strike him where he has taken no precautions."
    },
    {
      "front": "If your opponent is of _______ temperament, seek to irritate him.",
      "back": "If your opponent is of choleric temperament, seek to irritate him."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "Management of ____ is the same as management of ____. It is a matter of organization.",
      "back": "Management of many is the same as management of few. It is a matter of organization."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "The good fighters of old first put themselves beyond the possibility of ______, and then waited for an opportunity of defeating the enemy.",
      "back":
        "The good fighters of old first put themselves beyond the possibility of defeat, and then waited for an opportunity of defeating the enemy."
    },
    {
      "front": "Build your opponent a golden _____ to retreat across.",
      "back": "Build your opponent a golden bridge to retreat across."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "Swift as the _____. Quiet as the _____. Conquer like the _____. Steady as the ______.",
      "back":
        "Swift as the wind. Quiet as the forest. Conquer like the fire. Steady as the mountain."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "Now the reason the enlightened prince and the wise general conquer the enemy whenever they move and their achievements surpass those of ordinary men is ________.",
      "back":
        "Now the reason the enlightened prince and the wise general conquer the enemy whenever they move and their achievements surpass those of ordinary men is foreknowledge."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "And therefore those skilled in war bring the enemy to the field of battle and are not ______ there by him.",
      "back":
        "And therefore those skilled in war bring the enemy to the field of battle and are not brought there by him."
    },
    {
      "front": "There is no instance of a nation benefitting from _______ warfare.",
      "back": "There is no instance of a nation benefitting from prolonged warfare."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "When able to attack, we must seem _____; when using our forces, we must seem _____; when we are near, we must make the enemy believe we are far away; when far away, we must make him believe we are near.",
      "back":
        "When able to attack, we must seem unable; when using our forces, we must seem inactive; when we are near, we must make the enemy believe we are far away; when far away, we must make him believe we are near."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "When torrential water tosses boulders, it is because of its ______. When the strike of a hawk breaks the body of its prey, it is because of ______.",
      "back":
        "When torrential water tosses boulders, it is because of its momentum. When the strike of a hawk breaks the body of its prey, it is because of timing."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "______ operations are essential in war; upon them the army relies to make its every move.",
      "back":
        "Secret operations are essential in war; upon them the army relies to make its every move."
    },
    {
      "front": "He who knows when he can fight and when he cannot will be _______.",
      "back": "He who knows when he can fight and when he cannot will be victorious."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "Subtle and insubstantial, the expert leaves no _____; divinely mysterious, he is ______. Thus he is master of his enemy's fate.",
      "back":
        "Subtle and insubstantial, the expert leaves no trace; divinely mysterious, he is inaudible. Thus he is master of his enemy's fate."
    },
    {
      "front":
        "A skilled commander seeks victory from the ______ and does not demand it of his _______.",
      "back":
        "A skilled commander seeks victory from the situation and does not demand it of his subordinates."
    }
  ],
  "notes":
    "## The Art of War Quotes\n\nThis deck contains a list of quotes from Sun Tzu's The Art of War. The work focuses on aspects of warfase and how they apply to strategy and tactics. It has been used for years for military thinking, business tactics, legal strategy and management practices and remains one of the most influential strategy text in history.\n\n### ⚡️ How it works\nYour ability to recall these quotes will decrease over time. By reusing that material, it will strengthen in your memory. Your deck's recall bar will decrease over time. Studying these decks will replenish their strength. After repeated reviews, you will see each deck less and less.\n\n### 🚦 Getting Started\nTo get started, hit the 'Study Now' button and review the cards testing your ability to recall it as you go.\n\n### 📬 Questions\nFor questions, issues, or feedback, please contact hello@pensieve.space.\n"
}
